What's up, Falcons fans? Welcome back to
the Atlanta Falcons podcast network
presented by Microsoft Co-Pilot. The
2026 NFL draft is in the books. Tori,
our mission today, should we choose to
accept it, will be to recap all of the
picks, take a full assessment of the
2026 draft class, and honestly really
anything else we feel like talking
about. Sound like a plan?
>> I love it. Yes.
>> Awesome. Well, we're going to get into
that right after this. Greatness in the
NFL starts long before kickoff. It's
built in the quiet hours of preparation
with the discipline to turn insights
into action. The Atlanta Falcons rely on
Microsoft Copilot to turn preparation
into performance. With real time AI
powered insights right on the sideline,
coaches and players can make smarter,
faster decisions when it matters most.
From the field to the front office,
Microsoft Copilot is transforming how
the Atlanta Falcons prepare, strategize,
and win. This isn't just about football.
It's about unlocking potential wherever
the game is played. All right, we are
back. Tori, there was some action on day
three for the Atlanta Falcons.
>> Wasn't there.
>> They came in holding the uh pick 122,
>> which they didn't actually use. No,
>> because they traded it away. Yeah, look
at there. You got a trade.
>> Lookucky there. My uh postmidnight
proclamation that I hoped it would
happen, but I didn't want to get my
hopes up. It did happen.
>> Always get your hopes up. If life has
taught me anything, it's that you can
never go wrong getting your hopes hopes
up
>> cuz very few people have ever seen their
hopes and dreams dashed.
>> No, certainly not me.
>> No, definitely not.
>> Um, so they traded with the Las Vegas
Raiders 122. They got pick 134 in return
and 208.
>> So they picked up an extra uh sixth
round pick. So instead of coming out of
this with five for the second year in a
row, they ultimately made six picks.
>> Yeah.
>> Uh that pick at 134 was Oklahoma
linebacker Kendall Daniels.
>> Um and one of the very first things that
that I found out as I was just kind of
looking him up is this dude is tall.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Microsoft co-pilot tells me
that he is 6'5, which is in the 97th
percentile of all linebackers who were
measured at the NFL combine. That's an
inch taller than Devandre Campbell.
>> Yeah,
>> that's crazy.
>> That is That's a tall man right there.
>> That's insanely tall for Matt Ryan's
height,
>> right? It's so funny too because I was
talking to area scouts after the pick
and they were talking about their his
hybrid and versatile nature because he
came into college Oklahoma State as a
safety and even then he was a he was a
jumbo safety because he was still pretty
much just as tall. He was just
significantly smaller in size and
stature. They said he was about like 180
to 190. Well, then tack on two years
later, you're looking at a guy who is
6'5,
creeping up on 235, 240. So, it it he
ended up growing and into the position
of linebacker, but still has the
versatility of of kind of having this
safety background. He played it for two
going on three years before he really
transitioned. But even in the
transition, he he was more of a hybrid
linebacker safety look anyways. And it
was so funny because Will and I love we
love linebackers. You especially you
wanted you wanted Jacob Rodriguez at 48
and unfortunately he wasn't there but I
think you'll take Avon Trail.
>> Oh absolutely. I'm not mad about it.
>> Right. Yeah. So Will and I it was so
funny because we talk about linebackers
frequently because we love we we love
talking about linebackers and
>> I don't love lamp. I love linebackers.
>> I love Yes. We've also been quoting a
lot of anchor man recently. Uh but I I
say all this to say we were talking
about how how we couldn't have predicted
this pick knowing what we know about
Jeffrey and the type of linebacker that
he wants. How much success has Jeff had
in the last like six or seven years?
>> I hate that I did that. I didn't mean
to.
>> It's unavoidable now. Everybody's doing
it. Was it Z Zachariah Branch did it
earlier and didn't mean to. I did it.
Didn't mean to. So,
>> or no, I think Avon did it. I don't
know.
>> Yeah.
>> Everything's bleeding. Everything's
bleeding together. But
>> sixes and sevens, they're just running
together.
>> But Kendall Daniels is a Jeff Olrich guy
through and through. And that's not me
saying that, even though we did say
that. That's also Ian Cunningham saying
that this is a guy who you look at back
at like Voyer Lu and you look at just
recently Devon Diablo having a safety a
college safety turned this hybrid
linebacker
who's long and lanky and can run. That's
become kind of Jeff's calling card at
the linebacker position. And of a ton of
guys in this draft class, you look at
Kendall Daniels and the way he plays and
you're like, "Yep, that's a brick guy."
>> Oh, 100%. I told you like the only
reason that we didn't learn this sooner
is just we ran out of time, right? just
like we just didn't get to Kendall
Daniels
>> in the beast on the on the draft report,
you know, like but I'm looking at his
strengths here in in the beast and
>> first tall long athlete. Looks like a
basketball small forward.
>> Absolute check right there. Plays with
range to the sideline and when driving
down the line. Check. Has size and
athleticism to be a tight end matchup
defender. Like all of these are just
screaming. Jeffrich is gonna love this
dude and want him on his defense.
>> Yes, that's exactly it. I can't like
reiterate it enough that we should have
seen this.
>> We should have seen this coming.
>> When you like watch him play, turn on
the highlight tape. I immediately kind
of like was like, "Oh, he's, you know,
how everybody has kind of their favorite
player." Like the first round picks
always everybody's favorite because it's
usually the player they know the most
about throughout the draft process. But
by and large, when the draft class is
created, most people I feel like,
gravitate to like a day three person who
they didn't really know a ton about, but
then they turn on the film and they're
like,
>> you know who I really like is is that
Grady Jarrett guy in the fifth round,
you know, like
>> all that. That's going to be Kendall
Daniels for me.
>> I think so, too.
>> Um, he he has a couple of hits on his
highlights that are insane. It's like
the Javian Clowny hit against Michigan.
He's got one against Michigan as well.
>> Yeah. Um, the only thing that I'm afraid
about with Kendall Daniels is that I'm
going to call him Kaden Daniels because
I have wanted to do that about 15 times.
>> So, it's going to come eventually. It's
going to happen.
>> Everybody, please just excuse me in
advance.
>> Right. Yeah. There we go.
>> So, that kind of got us kicked off. I
was excited to see that pick. I didn't
really know a ton about Kendall Daniels,
but
>> he makes a lot of sense for what the
Falcons want to do, I think,
defensively. And the concern is maybe
what is the position he's going to play.
>> Yeah.
>> But Jeff has been dealing with that
concern
>> since he became an NFL coach. So like he
he does that all the time is is find a
home for these people who
>> maybe other coaches couldn't,
>> right? Yeah. And that's the thing is
like Jeff Albrich is really as we saw
with Jaylen Walker and like he wanted
him to master being an edge rusher. Like
I I do think that even though and this
is a theme of all these defensive guys
of like having position flexibility even
within that I I guarantee you that
they're going to come in and Jeff is
going to have them do one or two things.
Yep.
>> Because you don't want to overwhelm kind
of these young guys coming into the
league, especially like some of these
guys who really are on the younger side.
You look at Avon Terrell, Zachariah
Branch, I believe Kendall Daniels, too.
Uh Harold Perkins is, you know, he he
missed a whole year because of ACL. So
these are guys who do have a lot of
experience in their own right, but they
are on the younger side. So not
overwhelming them right when they get
into the league, I think is something
that's important for their own personal
development.
>> Absolutely. Um so that was the pick in
the fourth round. We then fast forward
to the sixth round. Uh Falcons still
did.
>> We didn't get any we didn't fast forward
anywhere. That fifth round took for
freaking ever.
>> That's a great point. Yeah. I don't know
what they they like went in reverse in
the fifth round. Like they just hit
pause in the whole shebang.
>> Yeah. I I could not It was like watching
paying dry that fifth round. I was like,
"Good God, let's let's get through
this."
>> So So the Falcons avoided it entirely,
but we still had to sit through the
process of it. Um and then at pick 208,
they added another defender, defensive
tackle Antario Thompson out of the
University of Washington. We got another
co-pilot inside here, but Antonio's most
productive game last season. Came
against Michigan. Michigan just kind of
catching a couple strays here, but he
had six tackles in the game, three solo.
Uh, and then earlier this season, he
also had four tackles against Purdue and
a sack. So, he is, I think, kind of like
this one gapping physical athletic
defensive tackle. I think a lot of fans
are familiar with this type of player in
this defense.
>> 100%. He he in comparison to kind of
some other guys who are in the class and
kind of what you think about a
prototypical defensive lineman, he is on
the smaller side. Just he he kind of
sometimes even looking back at photos of
him, he sometimes has like an edge
rusher look to him. He's not built like
big 306. He's like 6'2 30. He's like
built
>> he carries it well.
>> Carries it well. That's exactly what I
was looking for. So he's 306. What's
really fascinating about him is even
though he's like technically undersized
in in some ways he runs like a 473 at
306 lbs like this guy he had like a 1.72
>> 10 yard split like this is a guy who
when you talk about an attack style
front and kind of being on your first
step and really having that explosion
explosion off the snap that's a guy who
I think works within that. So I think it
was even Kevin Stansky or Ian Cunningham
said that this was somebody who they
felt like really worked within what they
were what they're wanting to do
schematically with that attack style
front. And I think that's the trade-off
is you some have you don't have someone
who's like the exact body type of maybe
what you're coveting but he makes up for
it in other ways. And it's in that
explosion. It's in that short area
quickness. It's in the footwork. Like
this is not a guy who has like cement
blocks on his feet. Like he he's up and
he's moving and he's agile.
>> Yeah. And I I think in a
rotationoriented front, right, like you
>> you can develop a player like this
without maybe exposing them to so many
snaps in a game where you're going to
feel the downside of that developmental
process, right? You can kind of pick and
choose your spots. where are we going to
set him up for success as he gains
confidence as he continues to learn? So,
yeah, I think again the athletic profile
and the trait. Did you hear Ian
Cunningham, he used the phrase sought
off when talking about uh anterior,
which
>> I'm looking at his wingspan.
>> It's over 80 and a half inches.
>> Yeah,
>> that that's crazy long to me.
>> he's got 33 and 12 inch arms.
>> The thing is he doesn't look like he's
long. Yeah, he's very long to me. He
doesn't look like it.
>> He doesn't look like like that's the
thing is like he doesn't he again he's
over 300 lb, but to me he doesn't look
he doesn't look like he's over 300 lb.
>> No. Yeah. So, he's going to be a really
interesting player. I think
>> I can't wait to see him in person on
>> because we can watch film all day long
and we can see kind of what they look
like, but until they get out there for
rookie mini camp, I'm He's the one of
everybody that I'm most excited to see
in person to see kind of what his build
actually is.
>> Cool. We're going to keep tabs on
Thompson.
>> Uh but seven picks later at pick 215,
the Falcons yet again went defense. It's
almost like that strategy episode that
we had a little while back, which you
should go listen to.
>> Yeah.
>> Paid off because they went defense. Um
Harold Perkins Jr. out of LSU,
linebacker, but
>> with amazing edge rush chops. And I
think that's kind of where you start
with um Harold Perkins Jr. And again,
another co-pilot insight, but he led uh
the team in sacks with four, and he also
tied for the team lead with eight
tackles for a loss and three
interceptions.
>> Amazing.
>> So, that's a playmaker a little bit.
>> I I really like this pick. I know that
this one was kind of a there were some
people that were a little bit eh on it,
but I love this pick in the sixth round
because I think that he has special
teams upside. I also think that he is
another guy who is just like this
athlete. Like we were just talking about
Ontario Thompson and I think Harold
Perkins, he again he's on the smaller
side. He is built more like a big
safety. He it's kind of similar to
Kendall Daniels and having kind of that
hybrid look about him. But what I like
about him too is he's he ran like a 443
at his proday which is in like the 91st
or some percentile of of his position
group. So he's he's quick. He moves
around the field very well and I he's
coming off of that ACL injury that
essentially put him out for almost all
of 2024 and I think even 2025 he's
getting his feet back under him. And
something that I was talking to scouts
about after the pick was
>> they're like the guy who he was that
freshman and sophomore year. He's a
freshman all-American and he's doing
he's an all a freshman all SEC guy.
>> Seven and a half sacks as a freshman.
Four force fumbles, three pass defenses,
72 tackles. like he was all over the
place.
>> They all believe that that guy is still
there. And the thing is is 2025
production. It wasn't like it was chump
change. Like he had good solid
production. It just wasn't what it was
in that freshman and sophomore year cuz
he's still coming off of a a significant
injury. So I think he's somebody who
>> I think is a bit of the the sleeper of
the group. I I think that he's somebody
who can carve out a role on special
teams, play really well special teams,
and see what happens as he continues to
grow in himself and in his body and and
kind of see where he lands a little bit.
He's he's a very intriguing guy for me,
too.
>> Yeah, absolutely. I'm a big believer in
the year after the year after kind of
with some of these ACL injuries. two
years after ACL injuries, two years
after after achilles injuries. Those are
that's when I think guys are like fully
back within their body and their mind.
>> Yeah, I think you can get back to the
field faster than maybe you could a
decade certainly two decades ago from
these types of injuries.
>> But now we're seeing enough of a sample
size where I think you really return to
the player that you were and that you
can still be
>> maybe a year removed from it,
>> right?
>> So yeah, I totally agree with that. I
think Perkins has a chance to when we
look back at this draft class in in
totality a couple of year like
>> the Brandon Doris almost of the class
where you're like, "Oh,
>> he became what we hoped he could and now
you're seeing a really good player at
the next level."
>> Yeah, I love it. I think it's I'm really
>> Yeah, catch catch me in like three years
and let's see what Harold Perkins is.
>> Love it. I will. I'm going to set a
reminder right now.
>> Right now on the phone. Um, finally with
their last pick, the Falcons selected
Ohio State offensive tackle Ethan
Onianwa.
>> There you go.
>> At pick 231, uh, who had a streak of 25
consecutive starts at tackle at Rice.
Um, actually, I believe it was 34.
>> I think it was 34.
>> Yeah. Yeah,
>> I think it was 34 uh consecutive, but he
had 25 at left tackle.
>> Yeah.
>> And nine at right tackle at Rice before
transferring to Ohio State for the 2025
season. Mh.
>> Thank you to co-pilot for that note. And
what what do you think like we expected
the Falcons to invest in the trenches a
little bit.
>> What was the first thing that jumped out
to you about Onian?
>> Oh my gosh, his size. He's massive. He's
like 333 lbs, 6'6. This is a guy who has
the body and the look about him that
you're like, "Yep, I'm good with that."
I and I think that even Ian Cunningham
said that he was talking to Bill
Callahan about like that was something
that he liked. He was like, I like the
look about him. I like the size. Can
potentially have even a bit more if he
really wanted to without losing some of
that, you know, some speed. But I I
think that when you're looking at this
pick in the seventh round, the Falcons
went into this off season I think like
how they went into this off seasonason
at offensive tackle is kind of not where
we are now. And yet offensive st
offensive tackle was always going to be
one of those things that's in the back
of your mind about like what you're
doing next with it. Because as we know
Jake Matthews, he's in the twilight of
his career. Knock on wood. like he
that's where he is. Falcons had Caleb
McGary retire. You signed Jawan Taylor,
but you just sign him on a one-year
deal. So, you were always kind of
thinking about what's next for the
offensive tackle. I'm not saying that
it's going to be Ethan, but I like the
idea of having a devel a true
developmental guy in here working with
Bill Callahan, working behind some
really good vets in Jake Matthews and
Jawan Taylor and seeing kind of what he
can do. Maybe you stash him on the
practice squad and you you have him take
the time to to learn the ropes of what
you need from from a tackle. Ian
Cunningham also talked about how at Ohio
State just this past year, he did kind
of have some position flexibility more
than he had previously. Moved into guard
a little bit. So, I like that part of
it. You can always use guys who can go
and play any of the five positions out
there. So, I I like I like this pick. I
think it makes sense for depth and you
kind of just see what happens.
>> Yeah, it's it's that last part with the
depth and the versatility that that I
really care about and ultimately what I
think could could determine um what the
Falcons do with him ultimately because I
I think it's very important to have the
versatility to play multiple spots if
you're a developmental player on the
offensive line and kind of a primary
depth piece is like that. You don't want
to be bringing 10 offensive linemen on
game days with you. You need to have
guys who can plug into multiple spots.
Uh so we will see if Oniiana can do
that. But those are the four guys. We
also have the two that they added on day
two, Avon Terrell and and Zachariah
Branch. So
>> how you feeling about the overall 2026
draft class, Tori?
>> I feel pretty good. I I'm glad that they
were able to get a six pick. I'm glad
that the trade worked out and I think
that they got two guys especially at the
top and Avon Terrell and Zachariah
Branch who can come in and be playmakers
for you immediately. I I think that guys
like Kendall Daniels has the opportunity
to really compete. Same with Harold
Perkins. I mean, go in there and see
what you can do. I I I think that this
was a really good draft. It's funny
because I think in day two it was like
very flashy Avon Trail. Mhm.
>> Zachariah branch. Whereas I think today,
day three, it was a bit more like meat
and potatoes. What do we need? How do we
fill it out? What can we do in depth?
Can we get some guys who can play
multiple spots, do multiple things, have
these athletes out there to go out and
compete? That's how I felt like I felt
like there were a difference in kind of
the goal of each day.
Yeah, it's I love a day three where
after we spend all of these weeks and
months just pouring over these these
draft prospects and kind of pretending
like we're we're pseudo draft scouts.
>> I love it when they just take guys that
I have never heard of before.
>> Yeah.
>> And then it's like, oh, let me find out
what this guy's all about. Yeah. Right.
But it also makes me be like, man, they
know so much more than we do. like
they're just in their back pocket
pulling out Interero Thompson and I'm
like
>> I didn't even know that man.
>> Yeah, I was looking him up in the beast
like yep that I excited to learn about
him.
>> So that that's always because we've
talked about this throughout the whole
process is I'm trying to just like as
much as I want to see the players they
add. trying to learn what Ian Cunningham
and Kevin Stfansky and and now Matt Ryan
and these guys what they like believe in
as a philosophy with roster building and
and things like that and you know I
think we can see the clear vision for a
lot of these players on the roster. Do
you have kind of an immediate as we sit
here in the hour after the draft wraps
up kind of like a snap judgment just
favorite pick?
I think that it I mean Avon Terrell like
tugged on the heartstrings and I didn't
think he was going to be there at 48. So
like the fact that you were able to get
him is is kind of a big deal for me
because I think he's someone who's going
to come in and I think he'll find a way
to have a starting spot wherever that is
whether it's inside or outside. It's
hard for me not to say him. Like it's
it's really especially just kind of like
>> again knowing the Terrell family like
knowing AJ knowing kind of what this
meant to them like there there is that
part of it like we're all human and I
think we saw that hug between those two
guys and you're just like oh my god this
is awesome. Uh I think
>> that'll be like the lingering moment
from this this year's draft.
>> 100%. You're talking about like
storylines of the draft. If that's not
one it's two.
>> Yeah. Like the way we remember Tac
McKinley holding up the picture of his
his grandma when he takes the stage like
I'm going to remember this in in the
same way.
>> Yeah. But I really like to go to go
through today. I really like the the
Kendall Daniels pick and I I like it a
lot because I think that linebacker was
such a a much bigger need than I think
people realize on this team. and and I
really thought that they needed to find
some who could compete in there and
that's what I think I think Kendall
Daniels will have the chance to do that.
>> Hold on to that thought because I want
to come I want to come back to it in in
just a minute. Okay.
>> But
>> I'll take Zachariah Branch then. you
know, like I I feel pretty good about
selecting him as my snap judgment
favorite pick because
>> a he's just going to be an incredibly
fun and exciting and electric player, I
think, to watch at the next level. I do
think he complements a lot of what the
Falcons already have in their offense.
>> Getting the chance to talk to him today,
which you will hear uh I believe on next
week's podcast,
>> he's a I think really smart, intelligent
dude who kind of has the his priorities
in the right place. and I think is going
to
be a positive impact in the locker room
like
>> yeah I think that
>> I was thinking of Jaylen Walker a lot as
we were talking I was like man you guys
are self starters who are just about
your business
>> that was what was so evident when we
were talking to Zachariah and it's you
know our first time meeting him we watch
him play all the time and he just
carried himself with a guy who as a guy
who I think seemed wise beyond his years
like he had regiments he had
>> like him and his dad had been doing all
these
physical therapy stuff and and taking
care of their body since like he was in
middle school. Like he was somebody who
knew what he wanted in this past year at
Georgia and went and did it. I think I
even said last night like he went into I
a scout told me that he went into
Georgia and it was like a business trip
for him.
>> Yep.
talking to him, you felt that like that
it was so evident talking to him and
talking to him about
>> his role within Georgia and what he got
from from this past year and how it set
him up to to be the 79th pick.
>> Yeah, he's like a veteran rookie.
>> He felt Yeah, again he felt older than
what he he was. Like this is a guy who
is again on the younger side. this in a
year in the time of like NIL, you're
seeing a lot of draft classes be older.
You're seeing a lot of guys who are like
five, six,
>> even seven years in college because you
can make money there now. So, why would
you leave? Like,
>> yeah.
>> So, you're seeing a lot of older guys.
>> Some of these guys are pretty young and
and Zachariah Branch carries himself
though as a guy much older. But they all
come from pretty established big
programs like each each member of this
draft class. You've got Clemson,
Georgia. I'm going to try to do this
right off the top of my head. Oklahoma
>> Ohio State, Washington, and who am I?
LSU. LSU. Thank you.
>> Those are all big programs, right? And
so even though they're younger players
age- wise, they have been around maybe
the right way to do it for a while now.
and and that is I think when we get to
training camp, I'm going to be so
fascinated to watch Zachariah Branch and
Avon and these guys because I think
they're going to carry themselves in a
way that almost affords them earlier
opportunities than they might otherwise
have. Like if they're rolling into
training camp, I know my stuff.
>> Where do I need to be? I'm running
there. I'm setting the pace. Like
>> they're going to see the field in camp
very quickly. Yeah. And then I think
that bodess well for them seeing the
field in the regular season early on.
How many guys do you think can make that
quick of an impact when we go into week
one? Like last year coming out of the
draft, I think we
>> felt pretty good about like, oh, you got
a few defensive starters. Yeah.
>> In this group,
>> what do you think we're looking at?
Maybe you don't have to put a number on
it if if you're not comfortable doing
that, but like
>> how many starters do you think we have
early in the season? Yeah, I think Avon
Terrell is going to fight for a or for a
starting spot. Zachariah Branch, it's
it's not a like he may not start, but
he's going to he's going to have a role
in this factor in the offense.
>> Yes. Like so just because Drake London
maybe gets the very f that's the one
thing about starters on the offense that
really and and on defense just starters
in general that ticks me off. It's like
people being mad like, "Oh, so and so
didn't start." And it's like, "Well,
maybe he wasn't in the package." Like,
>> you look at like a defensive tackle,
right? and and it's like, "Oh, they
played in 17 games. They started three."
>> And you're like, "Yeah, but they were
one of the most impactful players on
this defense."
>> Yeah. I I don't care about starts. I
care about the percentage of snaps you
take. Yeah. So, that's my spiel on that.
That's Don't get me started.
>> Coming to her to talk,
>> right? Yeah. Um but Avanton Trail, I
think, again, I go back inside, outside,
I think he's going to compete. It'll
depend on I think what Billy Bowman's
return to play looks like. It'll depend
on where the Falcons really value my
cues. depends on a couple of different
things, but Avon Trail is going to be in
the conversation for a starting spot
through training camp.
>> I think that Zachariah Branch obviously
he's going to have a role in this
offense. He's going to be he's a primary
guy, a true slot receiver that adds a
different element and layer to what the
Falcons offense can do. I think he has a
role right away. Uh Kendall Daniels, I
think he's going to be able to fight for
a spot. I I do I don't know what that's
gonna really shake out and look like,
but I do think that I would be surprised
if we didn't see him a lot in training
camp really working with in some
capacity
Divine Diablo and Jaylen Walker if they
do decide to kind of do some offball
stuff with Jaylen.
>> There's a lot of questions that I have
about linebacker and what they're doing
moving forward. Um cuz you don't want
like two of the same body types. And
there is a part of me that's like
Kendall Daniels and Divine Diablo or
>> we're getting there. We're getting
there.
>> Um and then I think, you know, starting
I think Harold Perkins has a has a real
lane to be a core special teams guy. I I
think that his speed and his tackling
ability and kind of like the physicality
of which he plays with, he's somebody
who I think I'm I'm kind of putting an
asterk beside of like that's a guy who
makes his way on special teams.
>> Yeah, I I think that all makes a lot of
sense. I I do think
>> um Avon is like you said, Nickel
outside. I I think he's going to be
somebody in we see in the secondary
sooner rather than later. And they've
got they're building a good secondary.
>> That secondary I think I I kept seeing
pictures of like
>> Xavier Watts, Billy Bowman, AJ Terrell,
Jesse Bates, and I'm like, dang. Like
that's a it's a high powered secondary.
Like it's it's going to be a fun
secondary to watch.
>> I like what you got, Justin Hood.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Justin Justin Hood. He's
probably sitting sitting back in his
office down the way just like Yeah.
>> Yeah.
the post the post-draft cigar just feet
up on the desk like the end of uh
>> one battle after another like um
>> yeah so I agree with that Zachariah
Branch totally agree I I do think that
uh
>> Kendall Daniels is
>> has the athleticism and the traits to
add something to this defense and I
think Perkins will have a a role whether
that's a sub package rusher or
>> Jaylen Walker right if they move him
around and get him back to that line.
But I could really see Perkins being the
guy that they have
>> earmarked is like,
>> "All right, you slide in there." That's
where we're bringing the juice off the
edge with you.
>> Yeah.
>> Jaylen, you slide back.
>> So much I think of what this defensive
lineup is going to look like, I think,
hinges on Jaylen Walker's usage there. I
I can't wait to talk to Jeff Olrich
about how because what you do with
Jaylen Walker has ripple effects.
>> 100%. So, our our final topic here is is
where do you still have question marks
on this roster? And I I think the
intention of that question is like what
don't the Falcons still have?
>> But I I want to use this to talk about
kind of that linebacker position because
we we just saw him add ostensibly too.
You know, I think Perkins is more of an
edge rusher. Um I think Daniels is a
little more of a like space moving alien
>> for lack of a better phrase.
>> Fascinating.
>> Yeah. Right. That's my, you know,
scientific professional opinion. But
>> I don't know if anybody is still like
the clear mic.
>> Like the role that divine has as your
will or Sam, you know, like
>> however you want to use him because I
think there is some interchangeability
there.
>> That to me is what like Daniel's is. So
there's overlap there. I think Jaylen is
maybe your biggerbodied
Mike per, but like his skill set
>> is more of like an outside linebacker,
>> right?
>> That that's to me I'm like so fascinated
to see how they plug
>> that specific hole,
>> right?
>> Cuz even Channing Tindle and Christian
Harris, they're not that body type,
>> right? like when I was doing the best
player available for day three, um Bryce
Botcher from Oregon was a guy that I I
put in there and if they had gone in
that direction, to me it would have made
a little more sense because you're like,
>> "Oh, I clearly see where you fit in this
defense." Now, again, I think Kendall
Daniels is maybe one of my like favorite
just surprise players that I've ever
seen cuz he looks like the predator
sometimes out there. He's just like
standing and looming over the play. I
can't wait to see him stand beside
Divine. Like they I I honestly wonder
how Yeah. I honestly wonder how like
they look standing side by side because
Divine is very tall and long and he kind
of has this like that's what he always
said. He was like, "I always feel like I
could just like stand in the way of some
throwing lanes and just like make make
quarterbacks hesitate."
>> All I'm I'm just thinking of Monsters
Inc., You know, when they're like trying
to scare the kids and go through the
doors and one's like
I'm just like picturing like Divine and
Kendall Daniels doing
>> basically what Divine did when he threw
his arm up on that one play against
Buffalo. That that was still one of the
crazier plays of 2025. But no, you're
exactly right because to me it's like,
okay, you go in with this group of of
linebackers.
>> Who has the green dot?
>> Mhm.
>> Who's who's calling things? Like who's
who's getting everybody lined up
>> at this point? Is it J is it Jaylen?
Like that's the question.
>> It feels like that's where they're
leaning.
>> I mean, and if that's that's the case,
I'm I'm fascinated to see kind of like
what Jeffrey
is because so much of what we saw Jaylen
do last year because Jeff Olrich was
like, I want him to specialize in one
thing. I want him to master one thing. I
wanted to be a traditional edge rusher.
They did do some different things with
him moving him across the line, but by
and large,
>> that was his goal. That was his that was
what he did in his first year. And now
I'm kind of like, is he is he moving
into this role of like what Kaden Ellis
was? I is that the And I think that was
oftent times even I go back to like when
Jaylen was drafted and we're having this
conversation in these very seats and I'm
like there's no way you're not going to
use Jaylen Walker's versatility there.
You It can't. I remember even saying
like, "Brick, I get it." Like you like
you want him to master being an edge
rusher, but there's no way when it all
comes down to it. And I think that like
there it's funny because it's funny how
things change because now we're sitting
here talking about moving Jaylen Walker
to a more traditional probably mic role
and I'm sitting here like, but he's been
doing so well. He's gotten so good at
it. Like so I am f that is the one thing
that I am the most fascinated about in
terms of roster construction and also
what it could mean for like Jeff as he's
putting his scheme together. Jaylen
Walker is the lynch pin.
>> Yeah, that that's he is just kind of the
X factor going into training camp to see
how they're going to look cuz they
>> they don't have that like thumper as
much as Kendall Daniels has some crazy
breathtaking hits. Absolutely.
>> But there's not that like, oh, I'm going
to go take on a block, an NFL offensive
lineman, jarm in the mouth, slide off of
him, make the tackle
>> and do that 12 times a game, you know?
Like that's not to say they can't do
that,
>> but again, I'm just kind of I'm
fascinated from a pure like puzzle piece
>> 100% standpoint.
>> Yeah. Yeah. I mean, I'm excited. I mean,
it draft always makes me pretty excited
for training camp because you you tend
to have all these questions around the
draft and you just kind of have to like
wait until training camp to get the
answers.
>> That's how the NFL gets you. It's the
drip drip. It's like as soon as you get
like an answer to one thing, it unlocks
15 other answers and you're like, "Yes,
we got to
>> and that is exactly where we sit right
now."
>> Yep. The Falcons will return in.
>> Um, so yeah. any other as they're kind
of doing UDFAS right now as we speak.
>> Are there any positions that they we
feel like they haven't even touched on
or addressed in a meaningful way in free
agency or the draft because they've done
a lot
>> done so much. This is almost it feels
like a completely different team. Like I
know the core pieces of Bjon Drake.
>> Yeah. But if we went down the roster and
highlighted all the addition it's it's
over a third
>> significant turnover.
>> Yeah. I think that you could still use
some bodies uh along the defensive
front. I still think that you could kind
of see what some like young edge
rushers, maybe some defensive tackles
definitely. I I kind of want to see just
some more bodies in there. Um
offensively though, I'm pretty chill. I
offensively I'm like cool. The only
question that I do have is center
because Ryan Nel obviously coming back
your starter, but we've seen it before
like what who who's behind him? Yep.
>> Like that's that's a big question for me
right now and I think that that probably
no one's really talking about, but
that's that's one that I would like to
see maybe a move made there to bring in
somebody who who can provide notable
like backup ability. Yeah, I I think you
could definitely add add depth there.
And then typically I'm I'm probably
looking at at receiver and corner. Like
just keep adding depth there, especially
with UDFA guys. Like if there's a high
upside receiver, go grab them. Bring
them in here. Like it's all gravy at
this point. Um but I would love to see
>> one or two of these guys that we're not
even talking about right now because we
don't know who they are,
>> right?
>> Flash and there usually is a couple in
training camp. So can't wait to see who
those guys will be. Yeah, exciting
stuff.
>> Um, before we wrap up, any closing
thoughts on on this draft class? It was
the first one under Ian Cunningham and
Kevin Stfansky.
>> How like how you want to leave this?
>> It's the first draft class, and I think
I said this last night, even. It's the
first draft class where I think that the
fan base has been like, "Yeah, we get
this." Like, we get this draft class and
we like it. Like, there there didn't
seem to be a whole lot of like
discontent. Is that a word? Yeah. Yeah.
there didn't seem to be as much
discontent as I feel like there normally
is in draft classes for this fan base
particularly love you guys but sometimes
it is a lot and I I think that
for this draft class Ian Cunningham's
first class regardless of how they end
up at least in this moment in time it
feels like the fan base is pretty cool
and chill with with this draft class
which is great
>> yeah not a lot of discontent Um, but
there is a lot of content and we have
all of it at Atlanta Falcons.com.
There's so so so much
>> so much content.
>> Tori's writing all of the why he fits
pieces. Uh, but we've got press
conferences with each of the multiple I
feel like press conferences
>> everyone.
>> We will have a lot of um analysis
pieces, just stories coming out of all
these conversations that we've been
having. Um, but I do just I want to say
thank you all so much for following
along this weekend. and know it's been a
long one as as the draft weekends always
are. Especially to the
>> 2 a.m. sickos.
>> The sickos, we love you guys.
>> Yeah. Jared, the king of the sickos over
staying up late to bring it all to you.
So, give him a big thanks. But
>> yeah, it was it was fun to kind of hear
from some of you at at 2 in the morning,
2:30 being like, I'm listening to it
right now. We just
>> makes it worth it a little bit. It warms
my heart.
>> We're sickos. We love our fellow sickos.
>> Um, so we're excited for this draft
class. We're excited for the upcoming
season. Uh, and and now we kind of turn
the page a little bit. So, here's what's
coming up next on the Atlanta Falcons
Podcast Network. Next time you get a
podcast, it will be on Tuesday when
Falcons Audible with Shock Rack and Dave
Archer are back to give their thoughts
on the Falcons draft class. You've heard
from us over the last few days. Now, you
get to hear from them. Then we will be
back on Friday with another episode of
the Friday Five. And we'll have a couple
of the exclusive interviews that we were
kind of talking about in today's episode
tagged on to the back end of that one.
And we will continue to talk in full
about just this draft class, maybe some
of the reactions as we get some
distance. Yeah.
>> To it. Um, but until then, thank you to
Tory Malaney. Thank you to Microsoft
Co-Pilot. I'm Will McFaten. Thank you
all so much. This has been a lot of fun
and we will see you next Friday.